Lelouch, a Britannian boy,
ブリタニアの少年 ルルーシュは
has been given a special power
by the mysterious girl C.C.
謎の少女C.C.から
特殊な能力を手に入れた
Geass.
ギアス…
The absolute power to compel
anyone to follow any order.
いかなる相手にでも命令を下せる
絶対遵守の力
For the sake of his younger sister, Nunnally,
妹 ナナリーの為
神聖ブリタニア帝国の破壊をもくろむ
ルルーシュ
Lelouch schemes to destroy
the Holy Britannian Empire.
Meanwhile, his best friend,
Suzaku Kururugi,
一方 彼の友人 枢木スザクは
帝国内での足場を築きかけていた
has established himself
within the Empire.
At this point, their respective destinies
may already be irrevocably set.
既にこの時 先行きの命運は必然として
約束されていたのかもしれない
Jibun wo sekai sae mo
The moment when I might be able...
自分を 世界さえも 変えてしまえそうな
Kaete shimae sou na shunkan wa
To change myself and even the world
瞬間は 何時も直ぐ傍に…
Itsumo sugu soba ni
It's always right there at my side
Kakusenu iradachi to
Even as I stood still, looking at myself
隠せぬ苛立ちと
Tachitsukusu jibun wo mitsume
With undisguised frustration
立ち尽くす自分を 見つめ
Mayoi nagara nayami nagara
Feeling lost, feeling anguished
迷いながら 悩みながら
Kuyami nagara kimereba ii sa
Feeling mournful, deciding what to do
悔やみながら 決めればいいさ
Kimi ga kureta kotoba hitotsu
All it took was a single word from you
君がくれた 言葉ひとつ
Tomadoi wa kiesari
And my uncertainty vanished
戸惑いは消え去り
Karappo datta boku no heya ni hikari ga sashita
You let the light shine into what was my empty room
からっぽだった 僕の部屋に 光が射した
Miageta oozora ga
The sky I had been looking up at...
見上げた大空が 青く澄み切って行く
Aoku sumikitte yuku
Cleared and turned blue
Tozashita madowo hiraku
And I decided to throw open...
閉ざした 窓を 開く事を決めた
Koto kimeta
The windows that were kept closed
Jibun wo sekai sae mo
The moment when I might be able...
自分を 世界さえも 変えてしまえそうな
Kaete shimae sou na shunkan wa
To change myself and even the world
瞬間を 感じる今ここに…
Kanjiru ima koko ni
I feel it right here with me
おぎゃー
おぎゃー おぎゃー…
THE BLACK KNIGHTS
私 トウキョウ租界を出るのって
初めてなんですよ
This is the first time
I've ever left the Tokyo settlement!
You wish Lelouch could
have come with us, don't you?
ルルーシュも来られると
良かったのにねえ
なっ！
Wha?!
良いではないか
今宵は夜通し語り明かそうぞ
Don't be shy!
Let's stay up all night talking!
We can tell each other which boys we like!
好きな男の子 教え合ったりさあ
いるんですか？　会長にそんな人
Do you have someone
like that, Ms. President?
ふんっ さあ ねえー
Hm... Who can say?
はっ！
大丈夫
It's all right.
河口湖はブリタニアの観光客も多いから
治安はいいって
Lots of Britannian tourists go to Lake
Kawaguchi, so security there is fine.
ゲットーみたいに怖くないよ
You don't have to be
scared of it, like the ghettos.
でも…
But...
一緒にいてあげるから
今度は置いてけぼりにしない
For this, we'll stay right with you and
won't leave you alone for a second.
う うん…
R- Right...
うわあー
おお…
どうした？　早く入れ
What's wrong? Hurry inside!
今からここが私達のアジトだ
As of now, this will be our hideout.
それは あんたが俺達と組むと
考えていいのか？
So, you think it's a good idea for you to join up with us?
ああ 私達は仲間だ
Yes. We're comrades, after all.
すっげえなあ　なんだこれ？
Holy cow!
What is this?
こんな物 いったいどうやって…
How did you manage to get this?
頼んだら譲ってくれたよ
I asked to a rather licentious
nobleman to let me have it for free.
道楽者の貴族が
You asked for it? Just like that?
頼んだって そんな簡単に…
It's all right. No strings attached.
大丈夫だ　足はつかない
おいおいっ　２階もあるぞ
Hey, it's got a second floor!
Don't you think this is a little too big for a car?
大き過ぎないか この車
On the other hand, they wouldn't be
expecting us in something like this.
でも 逆にこれぐらいの方が
盲点になるかも
テレビまでついてる
It's even got a TV!
So, how do things look at the scene?
現場はどうなっているんですか？
あ？
Right. I'm standing in front of the Lake
Kawaguchi convention center hotel.
何？
What's up?
Right. I'm standing in front of the Lake
Kawaguchi convention center hotel.
こちら河口湖の
コンベンションセンターホテル前です
Right. I'm standing in front of the Lake
Kawaguchi convention center hotel.
ホテルジャック犯は日本解放戦線を
名乗っており…
The hoteljackers have identified
themselves as the Japan Liberation Front...
はあ？
and have taken hostage members of
the Sakuradite allocation meeting,
なんだって
あ…
サクラダイト配分会議のメンバーと
居合わせた観光客
notable among which is Chairman James,
あ…
及び数人の従業員を人質にとっています
as well as several tourists who
happened to be there as well.
これが犯人から送られてきた映像です
This is footage which was taken by the perpetrators.
ジェームス議長の他
学生の姿も見受けられます
You can clearly see Chairman
James, as well as several students.
えっ 生徒会の…
From the student council!
ん？
The leader of the
criminal group claims to be...
犯行グループのリーダーは
草壁中佐と名乗る旧日本軍人です
Lt. Col. Kusakabe,
formerly of the old Japanese military.
あっ バカな！
That idiot!
高温超電導体の製造に
欠かす事のできないサクラダイトは
Sakuradite, without which high temperature
superconductors cannot be made,
世界の安全保障に直接関与する
重要な戦略物資です
is a vital strategic resource which
directly affects world security.
Area 11 is the world's
largest producer of Sakuradite,
ここエリア11は
世界最大のサクラダイト産地であり
市場への供給量は実に70％に達します
providing 70% of the total supply.
毎年ここで開催される
サクラダイト生産国会議では
Here, at the yearly international
meeting of Sakuradite producers,
サクラダイトの国際分配レートを
決定します
the allocation of Sakuradite
among nations is decided.
It would not be exaggerating
to say that the outcome...
その結果は 我がブリタニアと
諸外国とのパワーバランスそのもの
と言っても過言ではありません
determines the balance of power between
Britannia and the other nations of the world.
テロリストは国際世論が
この会議に寄せる関心の大きさを
It's believed the terrorists
are taking advantage...
of world interest in this meeting by
carrying out this violent hotel jacking.
狙いに入れてホテルジャックという
暴挙に訴えたものと思われます
日本解放戦線の草壁である
I am Kusakabe of the
Japan Liberation Front.
我々は日本の独立解放の為に
立ち上がった
We are taking this stand
for the liberation of Japan!
諸君は軍属ではないが ブリタニア人だ
我々を支配する者だ
You may not be soldiers,
but you are still Britannians!
You are the ones ruling us!
おとなしくしているならば良し
さもなくば…
If you keep quiet,
you'll be fine. If you don't!
ルル…
Lulu...
動いてきたな
So, they've made their move.
They're the biggest anti-Britannian force
in Japan, and they take pride in that.
日本最大の反ブリタニア勢力だからな
意地もあるんだろう
Compared to us?
俺達への？
Maybe.
かもな
喜ぶべきか悲しむべきか
I don't know whether to be
happy or sad about that.
They're all going
to end up getting killed.
あれじゃ 玉砕しかねえだろ
リヴァル
Rivalz?
あっ ルルーシュ！　あん…
Lelouch!
ルルーシュだ
発信音のあとにメッセージを
This is Lelouch.
Leave a message after the beep.
何やってんだよ　こんな時に！
What's he doing at a time like this?!
分かっている　しかし…
I know. But!
ホテルに繋がる橋は
メインを残して全て落とされました
All bridges connecting to the hotel except
the main one have been destroyed.
上空及び水中からの接近はいずれも失敗
Approaches from the air
or water have failed.
人質救出作戦を展開する為に
残されたルートは１つだけです
There's only one route left from which
to develop a hostage rescue plan.
んっ
コンベンションセンターホテルの
真下まで伸びてる
The main utilities tunnel running right
under the convention center hotel.
ライフラインのトンネル
これを使えば作戦通り
If we use this and then, following the
plan, destroy the foundation block,
基礎ブロックを破壊して
ホテルを水没させる事ができます
we can submerge the hotel.
このトンネルは物資搬入も兼ねている為
Since this tunnel was built
to take in supplies as well,
サザーランドならば突入可能
a Sutherland should
be able to get inside it.
敵にも備えはありましょうが
問題はありません
Even if the enemy has taken precautions,
it should be no problem.
ゴー！
Go!
今まで相手が使用した武器レベルなら
十分回避可能です
Considering the level of weapons
they've been using till now,
we'll have no problem avoiding them.
Enemies detected, moving through the
underground passage, as expected.
敵影捕捉
予測通り 地下坑道を移動して来ます
了解！　雷光 第２起動
左右四連脚部 固定
Roger that! Raikou, secondary startup!
Left and right quad-linkage legs, locked!
超電磁式留散弾重砲 電圧確認
Super electromagnetic shrapnel
cannon voltage, confirmed!
アンチナイトメアライフルと思われる
I think they've got anti-Knightmare rifles.
Spread out and break through them!
散開しつつ突破せよ
超電磁式留散弾重砲
Super electromagnetic shrapnel cannon, FIRE!
発射！
CHARGING
FIRE
What?!
何？
やった！
It works!
One shot!
一撃だ！
使えますな 雷光は！
The Raikou works!
Did you see that, Britannian pigs?!
見たか ブリタニアの豚ども
全滅？
Wiped out?!
敵はグラスゴーを改造した
リニアカノンを設置していたようです
It looks like they've modified
a Glasgow into a linear cannon!
So, there's no way
we can break through it?
突破は無理という事か
どうしますか？
要求通り政治犯の釈放と…
What do we do? If we release the
political prisoners like they demand...
テロリストに弱みを見せるな
We can't show weakness
to these terrorists!
しかし ユーフェミア様が
But Princess Euphemia is...
分かっている
I know!
その件は
まだ気づかれては いないはずです
They shouldn't have
figured it out yet.
人質の中に
ユーフェミア様がいるのが分かれば
If they knew that Princess Euphemia
is among the hostages,
必ずや交渉に使ってくるかと
they'd be sure to use her
as a bargaining chip.
会議には立ち会うだけでしたから
メンバーリストにも載っていませんし
She was just there as an observer,
so her name wasn't on the member list.
うふふっ
ああ 分かってるよ
Yes, I understand.
It'll work this time.
今度は うまくやる
However, I'm not his guardian.
でも 私は保護者なんかじゃないんだ
Can't A.S.E.E.C. help out
with the rescue operation?
僕達特派は救出作戦に
参加できないんですか？
申請はしてあるけど
うちは命令系統が違うイレギュラーだし
I asked them,
but we're an irregular unit with a
different chain of command. Besides...
それに…
イレヴンに作戦を任せる訳にはいかない
They can't entrust the
operation to an Eleven, right?
コーネリア殿下は
Princess Cornelia is very discriminating
about Britannians and Numbers.
ブリタニア人とナンバーズを
きっちり区別される方でねえ
受け入れてもらうには
まだ足りないんですね
We're still not accepted enough.
でもそれじゃ なんの為の
名誉ブリタニア人制度なんだか…
But then what's the point of even
having the honorary Britannian system?
お父様　シャーリーさんが…
Where does this go?
これどこに置く？
そっち そっち　運転席の方
Over there, near the driver's seat.
Hey! What about the boxes
I brought over here?
おーい　ここに置いといた箱は？
ただの観光なんですよ
She was just sightseeing!
She's still a student! But do these
terrorists care?! I won't forgive them!
まだ学生なのに
それをテロリストは無差別に…
許せない
シャーリーは…
娘は無事なんでしょうか？
Is Shirley...
Is my daughter all right?!
あの子は何も悪い事はしていないのに…
She hasn't done anything wrong!
ブリタニアと戦う為に組織は必要だ
しかし早過ぎる
We need organization
if we're to fight Britannia.
But this is too soon!
Still, we can't just do nothing, either.
でもこのまま放っておく訳にも…
コーネリアの性格なら
人質など無視して…
Knowing Cornelia,
she'll just sacrifice the hostages!
あっ ならなぜ動かない？　まさか…
Then why doesn't she move?
Is it possible?
Zero.
ゼロ
あっ
What will happen to the hostages?
人質 どうなるかな？
いずれにせよ　ブリタニア人を
生かしておく理由はないな
Eventually, there'll be no reason
to keep the Britannians alive.
そう… そうだよね
Yeah. Yeah, you're right.
おーい ゼロ
Hey Zero, should I hand
these out to everyone?
こいつ みんなに配っていいのか？
これさあ かっこいいとは思うんだけど
I mean, they look cool and all,
but we're just a resistance group, so...
俺達レジスタンスだし…
違う
Wrong!
あっ
We're not a resistance group!
私達はレジスタンスではない
じゃあ なんだよ？
Then what are we?
What we are trying to be...
are knights of justice!
私達が目指すもの… それは
正義の味方だ
To all special sniper teams.
Situation is hold. All team commanders...
特別狙撃小隊に達する　現状はホールド
各小隊長は通達を確認せよ
Those student hostages are in
the student council, aren't they?
人質の学生って
生徒会の人達なんでしょう？
交渉はまだ続けているから…
They'll keep the negotiations up for them.
I believe in the system.
僕は組織の人間です
個人的な感情より
組織の論理を優先します
I prefer the logic of systems
to personal emotions.
あ…
あっ
セシルさん　あそこ
Miss Cécile, look!
えっ？　何？
What?
That's...
あれは…
Are they going to?!
まさか人質を…
Don't...
やめろ…
Don't do it!
やめるんだ…
は…
NO-O-O-O!!!
やめろー！
So long as we receive
no answer to our demands,
我々の要求に対して
なんらかの返答がなされない限り
30分ごとに１人ずつ飛んでもらう
人質の為にも誠意ある対応を期待する
we will throw one hostage
off the roof every 30 minutes!
For the hostages' sake,
negotiations had better be in good faith!
That's their idea of a warning?
Savages!
見せしめとは… 野蛮人め
We could negotiate to just get the
women and children released first...
交渉に応じ女 子供だけでも
先に解放させては？
Forget it! Negotiate even once
and you just legitimize terrorism!
ダメだ！
一度でも交渉に応じれば
テロという手段を肯定する事になる
では 強攻策を？
Then we use force?
それはユーフェミア様の安全を
確保してからの事ではないでしょうか？
That would have to come after securing
Princess Euphemia's safety, wouldn't it?
うっ ユフィ 私は…
Euphy... I!
総督 ゼロが
Viceroy! It's Zero!
うっ
We've just received
a message from Zero!
ゼロから連絡が入りました
What? Car three was stolen by Zero?!
何？　３号車がゼロに盗まれた？
What was Gibson doing?!
ギブソンは何をやってたんだ
なんか 気がついたら盗られてたって
He says when he came to,
it had been taken.
Huh? Then where's car 3 now?
はあ？　で その３号車は？
Heading straight into the military.
軍のど真ん中へ
ええっ！
確認しました　ゼロです
狙撃しますか？
We confirm. It's Zero!
Should we open fire?
その状態で待機せよ
包囲完了後に逮捕する
Just stand by. We'll capture him
after he's surrounded.
So... What do you think
he meant by justice before?
なあ 彼が言う正義って
どういう意味なんだろうな？
I dunno, but we may die
before we find out.
さあ　でもその前に殺されるかも
後ろのみんなも逃げ場ないし
All our escape routes
have been cut off.
なんであのトレーラーを使わないんだ？
Why didn't we use that trailer?
アジトを人目に晒してどうするんだよ
Oh, so you want everyone
to see our hideout?!
ああ
Good point.
本当に信用していいの？
あのゼロって男
You sure we should
trust this Zero guy?
That's why I said
he looked shifty to me!
だから俺は怪しいって言ってんだ
Still, if anything happens,
I'll do something.
まっ いざとなったら
俺がなんとかするけど
コーネリア
ここで借りを返したいところだが
Cornelia, much as I'd like
to pay you back right here,
お前の使いどころはもっと先だ
you're more useful to me alive.
読み通りなら
ギアスを使うまでもないが
If you do what I predict,
won't need to use my Geass.
また会えたな ゼロ
We meet again, Zero.
Are you a member of
the Japan Liberation Front?
お前は日本解放戦線の
メンバーだったのか？
Or perhaps you intend to help us?
それとも協力するつもりか？
However, our concerns
take priority over yours.
しかし 今はこちらの都合を優先する
And so, for the death
of my half-brother Clovis...
義弟クロヴィスの仇
ここで討たせてもらう
I shall take my
vengeance right here!
コーネリア どちらを選ぶ？
Cornelia, which would you choose?
ん？
死んだクロヴィスと
生きているユーフェミア
Clovis, who is dead,
or Euphemia, who is alive?
あ…
All right, now I'm sure.
よし やはりそうか
第１条件はクリアされた
The first condition is now cleared.
You haven't changed, Cornelia.
相変わらずだな コーネリア
あなたは昔からユーフェミアを
溺愛していた　だから動けない
You've always doted on Euphemia.
That's why you won't act.
Your emotions are getting in the way.
情の尻尾が邪魔をする
うっ…
I'm going to save Euphemia for you.
ユーフェミアを救い出そう 私が
あっ
ゼロ 何を言っているのか分からないな
Zero, I have no idea
what you're talking about.
救ってみせる！　私なら！
I said I'd be able to save her!
あ…
ゼロだと？
Zero, you say?
はい　ブリタニア軍から連絡が
Yes, sir. We got word
from the Britannian forces!
To all forces! Let Zero pass!
I repeat, let Zero pass!
全部隊に達する　ゼロを通せ
繰り返す　ゼロを通せ
日本解放戦線が
私を同志として受け入れるか
Either the Japan Liberation Front
will either accept me as an ally...
or they're going
to see me as an obstacle.
それとも 邪魔者として扱うか
In either case,
I don't think they can resist...
いずれにせよ
ゼロに会いたいという誘惑
この心の動きに勝てるはずがない
という事は…
the temptation of meeting Zero.
And so...
Good.
いよしっ　作戦の前提条件は全てクリア
All the operation's preliminary
conditions have been cleared.
What are we doing, Viceroy?
どう致しますか？　総督
I thought that by letting Zero go,
ゼロが行く事によって
次の人質殺害までに
若干のゆとりが生まれるはずだ
we could buy some time before
the next hostage is executed.
So... This is our chance!
We can hit Zero at the same time!
なら これは好機だ！
ゼロもまとめて叩いてくれる
Ah, thanks so much
for that lovely order!
はーいー ご指名
ありがとうございま ははははっ
出していいって ランスロットを
They said you can
go for it, Lancelot!
え？
トンネル内をリニアカノンに向かって
突っ込めってさあ
They said to go after that
linear cannon in the tunnel!
Lloyd! You mean they're using him as
a decoy to make an opening for them?!
ロイドさん
それって うちをおとりにして
隙を作るって事ですか？
うーん
混乱に乗じて親衛隊が突っ込むみたい
Yup! Looks like they'll use the
confusion to send in the royal guard!
みたいってそんな…
What do you mean, looks like?!
Miss Cécile.
セシルさん
あ？
やります！　やらせて下さい！
I'll do it!
Please let me go!
みんなを助ける可能性があって
If they need me and Lancelot to
give them a chance to be saved,
今 僕とランスロットが
必要とされているなら やるべきです
then I'll do it!
Even if it means being a decoy!
それが例え おとりであろうと
CODE GEASS
Lelouch of the Rebellion
Warrant Officer Kururugi,
here is the outline of your mission.
枢木准尉 作戦概要を説明します
プライムサーチによると
According to prime search, the hostages
are located on the hotel's middle floor.
人質はホテルのミドルフロア
食糧貯蔵庫に閉じ込められている模様
It's believed they're locked
inside a food storage room.
嚮導兵器Z-01ランスロットは
Advanced prototype weapon Z-01 Lancelot...
ライフライントンネルを使って
ホテル地下へ移動
will use the utilities tunnel
to move under the hotel.
現着後 基礎ブロックを破壊し
ホテルを水没させる
Once on site, you will destroy the
foundation block and submerge the hotel.
人質の居る場所は８分はもつと
推測される
The floor with the hostages
should hold out for 8 minutes.
Hostage rescue and mop-up of the
terrorists will be handled by other units.
救出ならびにテロリストの掃射は
別部隊が担当する
なお 基礎の破壊にはヴァリスを使用
You will be using the V.A.R.I.S.
to destroy the foundation.
インパクトレールはアンチマテリアル
レベル３に設定
Set the impact rail
to anti-material level 3.
で 問題はトンネル内で待ち受けてる
リニアカノンだよね
So, the only question in this is that linear
cannon waiting for you in the tunnel.
Space is limited in there, so even the Lancelot
will only have an evasion rate of 47.8%
限定空間だから
ランスロットでも回避率は47.8％
本当にやるんですか？
Can he really do this?
Sure, just bring it back
if things get too rough.
うん　だから適当なところで戻って来てよ
ランスロットを壊す訳にはいかないしさ
You mustn't wreck the Lancelot!
適当なところ？
Too rough?
Yup!
うーん
Understood.
分かりました
スザク君　今度の日曜日
会長やニーナと河口湖に行くの
Suzaku, the president and Nina and I...
are going to Lake Kawaguchi
on Sunday. Wanna join us?
一緒に行かない？
Sorry. I have to work that day.
ごめん　その日は仕事が入ってて
ああ そっか　それじゃあ 仕方ないか
Really...
Well, I guess that can't be helped.
Still, thank you.
でもありがとう 誘ってくれて
本当に嬉しいよ
I really appreciate your inviting me.
作戦開始まであと12分
カウントダウンに入ります
12 minutes to operation start.
Starting countdown.
あっ うう… あっ
イ イレヴン
E- Eleven!
あっ 今 なんと言った？
What did you just say?!
ううっ
イレヴンだと？　我々は日本人だ
Eleven?! We're Japanese, dammit!
分かってるわよ　だからやめて！
We know! Just lay off her!
訂正しろ！　我々はイレヴンではない
Then correct her! We're not Elevens!
訂正するから
Fine, we'll correct her!
なんだその言い方は！
How dare you speak like that to me!
お前達 隣りまで来い！
じっくり教え込んでやる！
You three come with me to the next
room and I'll teach you a real lesson!
いやあっ！　いやあー！
No! NO!!!
あっ
ううん
I said get up!
立たんか こらあっ！
い… いやあっ！　いやあー！
No! NO!!!!
んんっ
おやめなさい
Stop that this instant!
Who the hell are you?!
なんだ 貴様？
ああっ！
わたくしを あなた達の
リーダーに会わせなさい
I demand that you
take me to your leader!
何？
What?!
いけません 副総督
Sub-Viceroy, no!
わたくしはブリタニア第三皇女
ユーフェミア・リ・ブリタニアです
I am Euphemia li Britannia,
third princess of the Empire!
ええっ…
Are you all right?
You're not hurt, are you?
あなた大丈夫？　怪我はない？
は… はい
No...
私と手を組むつもりはないか？
You have no intention
of joining me?
ならば素顔を見せてもらおう ゼロ
無礼であろう
Then show us your real face, Zero.
It's rude not to.
分かった
しかし その前に聞かせて欲しい
I understand. But before I do,
I'd like to ask you something.
What do you hope to
accomplish by this action?
お前はこの行動の果てに何を求めている
You need to ask?!
For this country and the world...
知れた事を　日本人がまだ
死んでいない事を内外に知らしめるのだ
to know that the
Japanese aren't dead yet!
古いな
How stale.
んんっ
お前達は古い　もう救えない
You people are obsolete.
There's no saving you.
きっ 貴様！
Why... Why you!
どういう意味かな？　ゼロ
What do you mean, Zero?
ＭＥブースト
M.E. boost.
ランスロット 発進！
Lancelot, launch!
反応 確認 敵ナイトメア １
移動速度は約２倍です
Reaction, confirmed! 1 enemy Knightmare!
It's twice as fast as the others!
構わん 同じ事だ！
Who cares?
It'll end up like the rest!
超電磁式留散弾重砲
Super electromagnetic shrapnel heavy cannon, FIRE!
発射！
CHARGING
FIRE
くっ
だから言ったじゃないですか！
I warned you about this!
うん　おとりじゃなくて
やりきっちゃうつもりだね
Right! He's running this for real
and not as a decoy!
中佐の元に先ほど連絡した
人質を連行しました
I've brought the hostage I radioed in
about before for the lieutenant colonel.
ユーフェミアと名乗っていますが
She claims to be Euphemia.
んっ
ゼロ もはや問答無用！
There's no point in talking anymore!
Die.
死ね
FIRE!
発射！
はっ
中佐！
Lt. Colonel!
あっ
落ち着け
Calm yourselves!
ゼロ
Zero!
中佐達は自決した
The colonel and the others
committed suicide.
行動の無意味さを悟ったのだ
They realized the pointlessness
of this operation.
あ…
ユーフェミア
民衆の為に人質をかって出たか？
Euphemia... You gave yourself up
for the sake of the commoners?
相変わらずだな
You haven't changed.
え？
何？　特派のナイトメアが？
What? A.S.E.E.C.'s
Knightmare is succeeding?
はい このまま行くと突破できそうです
Yes. At the rate he's going,
he'll break through soon.
ふん　期待していいのか？
Dare we hope?
All right! This level of
destructive power it can take!
よしっ この破壊力なら耐えられる
第５射も突破されました　信じられない
It's broken through salvo number 5!
I don't believe it!
Don't panic!
臆するな！　四連腕部自在砲台も展開
Deploy the quad-linkage free-fire
arm gun batteries as well!
ここは絶対防衛線である！
死守するんだ！
This is the final defense line!
We'll defend it with our lives!
くっ セシルさん
ここでヴァリスを使います
Miss Cécile, I'm going to use the V.A.R.I.S!
え？　待って それは危険よ
What? Wait, that's dangerous!
活動領域が狭まりました
爆風は覚悟の上です！
There's almost no room for me to move!
I'm prepared to take the blast!
ええっ…
貴様ら…
You!
副総督に就任されたと聞きました
ユーフェミア皇女殿下
I heard you're the sub-viceroy now,
Princess Euphemia.
喜ぶ事ではありません
It's not something I'm happy about.
Yes, because Clovis was killed.
That was my doing.
そう クロヴィスが死んだからですね
私が殺した
あ…
To the very end,
he begged for his life.
彼は最後まで私におもねり
命乞いをした
With the same mouth which
ordered the deaths of Elevens!
イレヴンを殺せと命じたその口で
だから兄を殺したのですか？
Is that why you
killed my brother?
いいや
No.
Then why?
では なぜ？
あの男がブリタニア皇帝の子供だから
Because he was a child
of the Britannian emperor.
え？
そういえば あなたも そうでしたね
That reminds me...
You're also one of his children, aren't you?
Maximum output!
I don't care if you wreck the guns!
出力全開！
砲身がいかれても構わん
絶対死守を敢行せよ！　粉砕！
Be ready to die
defending this spot!
SMASH HIM!
CHARGING
FIRE
くっ
あのイレヴン…
That Eleven...
ああ…
やりきったか？
He did it! Guilford!
ギルフォード！
はっ！
Right!
あっ まさか
It can't be!
The white-helmeted one from before!
あの時の白兜か
あっ
ユフィーッ！
EUPHY!
Guys!
みんなーっ！
よせっ 枢木准尉！
Warrant Officer Kururugi, no!
３番のカメラはどうなってる？
What about the cameras in car 3?
ゼロに取られちゃったじゃ…
Zero took them, so...
So, let's hope we get a signal!
だから 反応が欲しいんだよ！
どうした ゼロ？
What's wrong, Zero?
その為じゃなかったのか？
利用する為じゃ…
Wasn't that your plan?
To use this?
スザク君！
Suzaku!
ああ…
救えなかった
I couldn't save them!
僕は 僕は…
I... I... Again!
また！
来た
Got it!
えっ あれは？
Huh? What's that? It's Zero!
ゼロだ
ブリタニア人よ
No need to fear, my dear Britannians.
動じる事はない
ホテルに捕らわれていた人質は
全員救出した
All of the hostages from
the hotel have been saved.
あなた方の元へお返ししよう
I return them to you.
みんな
Guys!
良かったあ
Thank God!
ぬけぬけとよく言う
Of all the impudence!
お前に手出しをしたら
人質に逆戻りという事だろう
If we had attacked you, they just would have
become your hostages, wouldn't they?!
人々よ！
People!
Fear us or seek us, as you please!
我らを恐れ 求めるがいい
We are the Black Knights!
我らの名は… 黒の騎士団！
騎士団…
Knights?
皮肉だね
テロリストがナイトを名乗るなんて
Ironic, isn't it?
Terrorists calling themselves knights.
We Black Knights stand with all
those who do not have any weapons!
我々黒の騎士団は
武器を持たない全ての者の味方である
イレヴンだろうと
ブリタニア人であろうと
Whether they be Elevens or Britannians!
日本解放戦線は卑劣にも
ブリタニアの民間人を人質に取り
The Japan Liberation Front cowardly
took Britannian civilians hostage...
無残に殺害した　無意味な行為だ
ゆえに我々が制裁を下した
and then cruelly executed them.
It was a meaningless act,
and so we have punished them!
えっ
当然です　このまま流さないと
You heard me right!
Let it run!
責任？　そんなものは私が取ります
Responsibility?!
I'LL take responsibility!
クロヴィス前総督も同じだ
武器を持たぬイレヴンの虐殺を命じた
Just as I punished
former viceroy Clovis.
He ordered the slaughter
of unarmed Elevens.
このような残虐行為を
見過ごす訳にはいかない
We could not stand by and allow
this cruel action to take place.
And so, we mete out punishment.
ゆえに制裁を加えたのだ
私は戦いを否定しない
I will not repudiate fighting.
しかし 強い者が弱い者を
一方的に殺す事は 断じて許さない
But neither will I stand for a one-sided
slaughter of the weak by the strong!
撃っていいのは
撃たれる覚悟のある奴だけだ
The only people who should kill are
those prepared to die themselves!
Where those with power attack those
without, we shall appear again!
我々は 力ある者が力なき者を襲う時
再び現れるだろう
No matter how great a power
our enemy may possess!
たとえその敵がどれだけ大きな力を
持っているとしても
正義の… 味方？
Knights of justice...
力ある者よ 我を恐れよ
Those of you with power, fear me!
力なき者よ 我を求めよ
Those who have none, seek me!
For we, the Black Knights,
shall judge this world!
世界は我々黒の騎士団が 裁く！
行けどもけものみち 獅子よ虎よと吠え
Yukedomo kemonomichi
Walking along the animal path
Shishi yotorayoto hoe
Roaring with the lions and tigers
茜射す空の 彼方にまほろば
Akane sasu sora no kanata ni mahoroba
Paradise lying far across a sky dyed red
幽囚の孤獨に 彷徨う青春は
Yuushuu no kodoku ni samayou seishun wa
To a youth wandering, imprisoned in loneliness
弱さと怒りが姿無き敵ですか
Yowasato ikari ga sugata naki teki desu ka
Are weakness and hatred shapeless enemies?
父よ 未だ我は
Chichi yo madaware wa
Oh father, I am still...
己を知りがたし
Onore wo shirigatashi
Learning who I am
先立つ兄らの
Sakidatsu anira no
As I pursue the backs I no longer see
見えない背中を追えば
Mienai senakawo oeba
Of the elder brothers who have gone before me
迷いの一夜に明星は誘う
Mayoi no hitoyo ni
In the night I spend lost
Myoujou wa izanau
The morning star beckons to me
死して終わらぬ
Shi shite owaranu
This will not end in my death
夢を焦がれども
Yume wo kogaredomo
I long for my dream
確かな君こそ我が命
Tashika na kimi kosowaga inochi
My faith in you sustains my life
Reppu no kouya de
In the windswept wilderness
烈風の荒野で 蝶よ花よと生き
Chou yo hanayoto iki
Living with the butterflies and flowers
とこしえの春に 咲き添うまぼろし
Tokoshie no haru ni sakisou maboroshi
Blooming together in a mirage of eternal Spring
混獨の純潔 この身は汚れても
Kondaku nojunketsu
If my purity seems muddied
Kono mi wayogoretemo
And my body seems filthy
心の錦を信じていてください
Kokoro no nishiki wo shinjiteite kudasai
Please believe in the finery within my heart
母よ けして我は
Hahayo kesshite ware wa namidawo misene domo
Oh mother, I will show no tears
涙を見せねども
足下の草に露は消えもせで
Ashimoto no
They vanish like...
Kusa ni tsuyu wa kiemosede
The dew in the grass beneath my feet
ツイている　天は俺に味方した
I was lucky.
Heaven must truly be on my side.
まさかコーネリアの弱点が
捕虜になっていたとは
I never expected Cornelia's weakness
would be among the hostages.
ユーフェミアという弱点が
A weakness named Euphemia.
さあ ここからが黒の騎士団の
俺の反撃だ
From now on. the Black Knights
shall become my counterattack.
俺を閉じ込めた世界に
On the world I'm trapped in...
そして動かなかった俺自身の心に
as well as on my own unmoving heart.